<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reading on Varun Kumar</title>
    <link>https://varunksaini.com/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reading on Varun Kumar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 07:17:22 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://varunksaini.com/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Everybody Lies by Seth Stevens-Davidowitz</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/everybody-lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 07:17:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/everybody-lies/</guid>
      <description>Everybody Lies by Seth Stephens-Davidowitz is an insightful and thought-provoking book that sheds light on the hidden truths of human behavior, using big data analysis.
Summary The book explores how the internet and the proliferation of digital technology have given us a window into the true nature of people&amp;rsquo;s thoughts, desires, and actions. By analyzing data from search engines, social media platforms, and other online sources, the author uncovers surprising insights about what people really think and do, even when they may not want to admit it in public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics in One Lesson - by Henry Hazlitt</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/economics-in-one-lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 10:36:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/economics-in-one-lesson/</guid>
      <description>I was looking to read a book about economics from some time. I came across this book and immediately picked it up. I am really glad that I decided to read this book. This book is one of the most concise and thoughtful work on economics.
summary of the book Thoughts Nobel laureate F.A. Hayek said, there is &amp;ldquo;no other modern book from which the intelligent layman can learn so much about the basic truths of economics in so short a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amusing Ourselves to Death: Public Discourse In The Age Of Show Business by  Neil Postman</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/amusing-ourselves-to-death-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 07:24:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/amusing-ourselves-to-death-book/</guid>
      <description>Amusing Ourselves to Death: Public Discourse in the Age of Show Business is a book by educator Neil Postman. I came to know about this book from one of seenunseen episodes. you can see a pattern here, much of my reading recently is inspired by that single podcast.
summary of the book: This book takes reader through the history media and how changes in media impacted sociatey in general(good or bad).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masala Lab - The Science Of Indian Cooking by Krish Ashok</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/masala-lab-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 07:23:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/masala-lab-book/</guid>
      <description>I like cooking and try to cook at least 1 time every week. I am not a recipe follower and like to add my own touch to food I am going. I heard about this book on seenunseen and decided to give it a read. I liked tone and structure of book and in fact learned about few things that were just intution eralier.
summary of the book: The book is divided into 8 chapters:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020: My Reading List</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/books-this-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 06:49:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/books-this-year/</guid>
      <description>These are the books that I have read so far this year.
  Outlier by Malcolm Gladwell
  The Gardener and the Carpenter: What the New Science of Child Development Tells Us About the Relationship Between Parents and Children by Alison Gopnik
  Nudge: Improving Decisions About Health, Wealth, and Happiness by Richard H. Thaler and Cass R. Sunstein
  Peak: Secrets from the New Science of Expertise by Anders Ericsson</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
