<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>general on Varun Kumar</title>
    <link>https://varunksaini.com/tags/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in general on Varun Kumar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 07:24:46 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://varunksaini.com/tags/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amusing Ourselves to Death Book</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/amusing-ourselves-to-death-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 07:24:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/amusing-ourselves-to-death-book/</guid>
      <description>Amusing Ourselves to Death: Public Discourse in the Age of Show Business is a book by educator Neil Postman. I came to know about this book from one of seenunseen episodes. you can see a pattern here, much of my reading recently is inspired by that single podcast.
summary of the book: This book takes reader through the history media and how changes in media impacted sociatey in general(good or bad).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review - Software Engineering at Google: Lessons Learned from Programming Over Time</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/book-review-seag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 09:43:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/book-review-seag/</guid>
      <description>The premise of the book is to draw lessons from software engineering at google and present them in a digestible manner, this book does a good job of that. . Chapters in this book are written by a different people from Google(ex-Google) and that brings a fresh perspective to this book.
The book reintroduces the term engineering with a new definition: programming integrated over time, or how to make software programs stand the test of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020: My Reading List</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/books-this-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 06:49:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/books-this-year/</guid>
      <description>These are the books that I have read so far this year.
  Outlier by Malcolm Gladwell
  The Gardener and the Carpenter: What the New Science of Child Development Tells Us About the Relationship Between Parents and Children by Alison Gopnik
  Nudge: Improving Decisions About Health, Wealth, and Happiness by Richard H. Thaler and Cass R. Sunstein
  Peak: Secrets from the New Science of Expertise by Anders Ericsson</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Home Office Setup</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/my-home-office-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 19:32:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/my-home-office-setup/</guid>
      <description>I have been working from home for last 4 years. Initially I thought that I can get by a laptop and couch. But that&amp;rsquo;s not how it played out. Very soon I realized that I need to have a proper home office setup if I want to work from home for a long duration. And here I am after 4 years. I have acquired quite a few things, and this is a running list of that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a quick introduction to standard streams, file descriptors, and redirection</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/a-quick-introduction-to-standard-streams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 13:47:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/a-quick-introduction-to-standard-streams/</guid>
      <description>standard streams are pre connected input and output communication channels between a program and its environment.
The three standard streams are stdin, stdout, and stderr.
File descriptors are handles that are used to access an input or output file, stream, pipe, socket, device, network interface etc. File descriptors work by providing a layer of abstraction between an actual hardware device and a special file created by the kernel for the device, populated by udev, and stored in the /dev directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>standard bash error codes</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/standard-bash-error-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 06:33:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/standard-bash-error-codes/</guid>
      <description>Exit codes in bash indicate the previous command&amp;rsquo;s termination status. 0 indicates that command completion was successful while 1 indicates that command execution failed.
We can check the exit code generated by last command by using $?
$ echo $? It&amp;rsquo;s not only 1 that indicates unsuccessful completion, anything greater than 1 is a sign of command failure. Standard error code are listed here:
   Exit Code Description     0 Successful execution   1 Unsuccessful execution catchall   2 Incorrect use of shell builtin   126 Command can not execute   127 Command not Found   128 Incorrect exit code argument   128 + num Fatal error signal &amp;ldquo;num&amp;rdquo;   130 Script killed with CTRL + C   255+ Exit code is out of range    Note: Exit code is an integer value between 0 and/or 255.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
