<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Varun Kumar</title>
    <link>https://varunksaini.com/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Varun Kumar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 06:40:31 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://varunksaini.com/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Workspaces in Go and recent gotcha</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/using-workspaces-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 06:40:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/using-workspaces-go/</guid>
      <description>Go 1.18 adds workspace mode to Go, which lets you work on multiple modules simultaneously.
Workspaces
Go workspaces helps to work with several modules in a Go project. When you create a go.work file, Go runs through the list of modules listed in the workspace, and creates a single list of dependencies. If go.mod files have replace directives, Go will also take them into account.
The go.work file has use and replace directives that override the individual go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guessing Game from Rust book in  Go</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/guessing-game-rust-and-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 07:31:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/guessing-game-rust-and-go/</guid>
      <description>This year I have been finding some time and learning Rust. I am going to write about my learning journey in another post. Today I want to talk about converting Guessing game from Rust book to Go. It was a fun and quick exercise. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see that both programms are almost same in size. Here is Rust code from Book.
usestd::io;userand::Rng;usestd::cmp::Ordering;fn main(){println!(&amp;#34;Guess the number!!&amp;#34;);letsecret_number=rand::thread_rng().gen_range(1..=100);loop{println!(&amp;#34;Please input your guess.&amp;#34;);letmutguess=String::new();io::stdin().read_line(&amp;amp;mutguess).expect(&amp;#34;Failed to read line&amp;#34;);letguess: u32 =matchguess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviewing Network Programming With Go by Adam Woodbeck</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/network-programming-with-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 09:57:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/network-programming-with-go/</guid>
      <description>A good primer on how to write network programs using Go programming language. Author starts by talking about TCP/IP, UDP, and other networking stuff. Once the basic theory is out of way, author builds network services using TCP and UDP. In later chapters, author talks about deployment, cloud, and observability for services.
Overall, I liked this book a lot and learned a few things too. Writing style is very approachable and fun.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
