<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>book on Varun Kumar</title>
    <link>https://varunksaini.com/tags/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book on Varun Kumar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 21:41:44 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://varunksaini.com/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shoe Dog Phil Knight</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/shoe-dog-phil-knight/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 21:41:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/shoe-dog-phil-knight/</guid>
      <description>Shoe Dog is memoir by Nike founder Phil Knight. Book talks about how he founded Blue Ribbons and then fought for the company. How Nike got its signature shoes and what else happened in this journey.
Things I liked Book is exhaustive and talks about both successes and failures. Language of the book is easy and there is a flow to the story.
Thing I wished were there I wish author talked about whole Jordan saga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Things We Make: The Unknown History of Invention from Cathedrals to Soda Cans by Bill Hammock</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/book-review-things-we-make/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 08:18:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/book-review-things-we-make/</guid>
      <description>Book Review: The Things We Make: The Unknown History of Invention from Cathedrals to Soda Cans by Bill Hammock In &amp;ldquo;The Things We Make: The Unknown History of Invention from Cathedrals to Soda Cans,&amp;rdquo; Bill Hammock, also known as the &amp;ldquo;Engineer Guy,&amp;rdquo; takes readers on an intriguing journey through the hidden histories of everyday objects. This book is not just a collection of facts about engineering marvels; it’s a narrative that weaves together the art, science, and human ingenuity behind inventions that have shaped our world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Subtle Art of Not Giving F**k</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/book-review-subtle-art-not-giving-fuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 21:29:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/book-review-subtle-art-not-giving-fuck/</guid>
      <description>I in fact listened to this book. I borrowed book from library using Libby app. I was aware of the app but only started using it recently. This is the first book that I read/listened to. It was not a bad experience, but I still prefer reading physical books and collectiong the good one. Anyway, here is my review of the book, I took some help from ChatGPT for this review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South vs North Nilakantan RS</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/south-vs-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 07:38:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/south-vs-north/</guid>
      <description>South vs North by Nilakantan RS is a well research and fact based comparison of differences between South side of India and North side of India. This books not only talks about the issues, but gives data abou those problem and then in the end books also suggests way to fix some of these things. India being such a big and populous country, bound to have many issues. This books throws lights on many of these issues and how the socioeconomic differences between South India and North India play a part in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everybody Lies by Seth Stevens-Davidowitz</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/everybody-lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 07:17:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/everybody-lies/</guid>
      <description>Everybody Lies by Seth Stephens-Davidowitz is an insightful and thought-provoking book that sheds light on the hidden truths of human behavior, using big data analysis.
Summary The book explores how the internet and the proliferation of digital technology have given us a window into the true nature of people&amp;rsquo;s thoughts, desires, and actions. By analyzing data from search engines, social media platforms, and other online sources, the author uncovers surprising insights about what people really think and do, even when they may not want to admit it in public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics in One Lesson - by Henry Hazlitt</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/economics-in-one-lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 10:36:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/economics-in-one-lesson/</guid>
      <description>I was looking to read a book about economics from some time. I came across this book and immediately picked it up. I am really glad that I decided to read this book. This book is one of the most concise and thoughtful work on economics.
summary of the book Thoughts Nobel laureate F.A. Hayek said, there is &amp;ldquo;no other modern book from which the intelligent layman can learn so much about the basic truths of economics in so short a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amusing Ourselves to Death: Public Discourse In The Age Of Show Business by  Neil Postman</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/amusing-ourselves-to-death-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 07:24:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/amusing-ourselves-to-death-book/</guid>
      <description>Amusing Ourselves to Death: Public Discourse in the Age of Show Business is a book by educator Neil Postman. I came to know about this book from one of seenunseen episodes. you can see a pattern here, much of my reading recently is inspired by that single podcast.
summary of the book: This book takes reader through the history media and how changes in media impacted sociatey in general(good or bad).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviewing Network Programming With Go by Adam Woodbeck</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/network-programming-with-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 09:57:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/network-programming-with-go/</guid>
      <description>A good primer on how to write network programs using Go programming language. Author starts by talking about TCP/IP, UDP, and other networking stuff. Once the basic theory is out of way, author builds network services using TCP and UDP. In later chapters, author talks about deployment, cloud, and observability for services.
Overall, I liked this book a lot and learned a few things too. Writing style is very approachable and fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review - Software Engineering at Google: Lessons Learned from Programming Over Time</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/book-review-seag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 09:43:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/book-review-seag/</guid>
      <description>The premise of the book is to draw lessons from software engineering at google and present them in a digestible manner, this book does a good job of that. . Chapters in this book are written by a different people from Google(ex-Google) and that brings a fresh perspective to this book.
The book reintroduces the term engineering with a new definition: programming integrated over time, or how to make software programs stand the test of time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
