<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reviews on Varun Kumar</title>
    <link>https://varunksaini.com/tags/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reviews on Varun Kumar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 08:18:28 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://varunksaini.com/tags/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Things We Make: The Unknown History of Invention from Cathedrals to Soda Cans by Bill Hammock</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/book-review-things-we-make/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 08:18:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/book-review-things-we-make/</guid>
      <description>Book Review: The Things We Make: The Unknown History of Invention from Cathedrals to Soda Cans by Bill Hammock In &amp;ldquo;The Things We Make: The Unknown History of Invention from Cathedrals to Soda Cans,&amp;rdquo; Bill Hammock, also known as the &amp;ldquo;Engineer Guy,&amp;rdquo; takes readers on an intriguing journey through the hidden histories of everyday objects. This book is not just a collection of facts about engineering marvels; it’s a narrative that weaves together the art, science, and human ingenuity behind inventions that have shaped our world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masala Lab - The Science Of Indian Cooking by Krish Ashok</title>
      <link>https://varunksaini.com/masala-lab-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 07:23:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://varunksaini.com/masala-lab-book/</guid>
      <description>I like cooking and try to cook at least 1 time every week. I am not a recipe follower and like to add my own touch to food I am going. I heard about this book on seenunseen and decided to give it a read. I liked tone and structure of book and in fact learned about few things that were just intution eralier.
summary of the book: The book is divided into 8 chapters:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
